# **Prateek Singh**

## **Product Designer**

www.prateeksingh.in

9711960199 | 8467884193

### **Skills**

Interaction Design, Strategic
Design, Research Methods &
Processes, Prototyping,
Information Architecture, User
Journey Mapping, Accessibility,
Usability testing

## **Tools**

**Figma** 

Adobe XD

Photoshop

HTML5

CSS3

Sketch

Microsoft Office

Premiere Pro

## Recognition

### Wongdoody Insta Award

Awarded for my contribution in a high demand client work.

#### **Full Stack Designer**

Completed a demanding training to earn the above certificate.

Infosys Certified Digital Accessibility Associate.

## **Hobbies**

Blogging Cycling Cricket 3D Printing

Esports

A designer by passion and education. I have been working as a Lead UX Designer at Wongdoody since after completing my Master's in 2020. I have a knack for Tech and my academics and work experiences have provided me with just the right tools to humanize it.

## **Work Experience**

## Wongdoody | Infosys

Lead Experience Designer

Jan 2021 - Present

....

Worked with multiple Fortune 500 clients, designing across a variety of domains. Meanwhile, continuously skilling up through the in-house trainings and initiatives.

• US Based tech giant

Working with a team of designers to create, maintain and update a major sales portal and system of products around it. Lead multiple verticals from conception to realization.

• South Korean Multinational Conglomerate Lead two verticals within the project. Designed 10+ standalone widgets and the web-interface for a call tracker API. Received a 94% approval rate from client.

Dashboard for Logistics Company
 Designed and presented native flows for a white-label product.

#### **Freelance Designer**

Jul 2018- Dec 2020

Worked across multiple design domains including UX, architecture, branding and Industrial Design. The clientele being mostly early stage startups e.g., ORIS & SOMA.

## **Internships**

#### **Evinix Design Concepts Pvt Ltd, Ghaziabad**

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

Product Design Intern

Designed and prototyped 3 articles which later made into mass-manufacturing. Documented the entire process and presented to the graduating class of M.Des students.

#### Spacematters, Delhi

Jan 2017 - Jul 2017

Research and Documentation Intern

Interviewed 30+ people and documented several processes of a native wood craft — likhai. Co-authored the only comprehensive document existing for the apparently lost wood craft.

#### **Delhi Development Authority**

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

Transportation Design Intern

Researched vehicular density and conducted traffic analysis along a proposed route in Delhi. Later, worked with Transport Planners to design and develop the said corridors and presented the design to the Lieutenant Governor of Delhi.

#### **Education**

## **Special Program for Strategic Insights**

Mar 2022 - present

Center of Complexity

Rhode Island School of Design

#### M.Des | Industrial and Product Design

2020

Department of Industrial Design,

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi — First Class with Distinction

### **Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch)**

2018

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi — First Class

#### HSC, CBSE

Delhi Public School, Lucknow 89.3%